Dan Thompson II

Software Engineer with 2+ years of demonstrated expertise in developing and implementing technical solutions. Collaborative and team-focused, working alongside engineers, product, and design to combine ideas to make the best solution. Searching for opportunities to build great user experiences with even greater people.

Experience

Software Engineer 3

9/2022 - 8/2023

eFuse | Columbus, Ohio

Individual Contributor using MongoDB, Express, Redis, Node.js, React, and GraphQL to build an esports tournament platform and contributed to the growth of EsportsGG by improving SEO and analytics.

- Utilized third-party tools to create CRUD interfaces to edit tournament and user information when product leadership needed a quick yet effective solution, saving money and time as this functionality did not have to go through a design process to be included in the product.
- Worked to create a server-side student verification process by sending user-provided information in a payload to a
 third-party API and then parsed those records to determine enrollment status. This functionality is used to process hundreds
 of academic records, completely replacing a manual review process.
- Delivered a thoroughly tested tournament leaderboard, integrated with a third-party publisher's API, within a two-sprint deadline. Made possible by a high level of communication between engineering, design, and product and by utilizing various toolsets.
- Directly contributed to a 500% increase in newsletter signups by building a process that tracks the read percentage of an article; readers are prompted to sign up once they have read 80% of an article.
- Designed and implemented an analytics process that measured the percentage of an article being read by each user.
- Collaborated with the product team to help grow the EsportsGG audience to over 1,000,000 monthly page views.
- Scoped and proposed solutions around SEO and site-wide analytics problems.
- Updating JSON-LD schemas to conform to Google's SEO recommendations, resulting in news articles correctly appearing in Google search results.

Engineer

1/2022 - 9/2022

RevLocal | Granville, Ohio

Individual Contributor learning how to contribute best, creating solutions with C# and Salesforce to facilitate sales and marketing.

- While pairing, created a visual flow that retrieves information from a customer's account and requests information related to requested services from the account manager; based on the responses, generated the plans for the services requested.
- Built a process to manage company-created email addresses for customers utilizing Salesforce and .NET APIs by generating and sending SOAP payloads to a third-party email service.
- Made payment process compliant with PCI standards by creating a technical solution that automatically pauses call recording during payment processing.

Equipment Service Technician Intern

05/2021 - 07/2021

Honda Manufacturing | Marysville, Ohio

Intern learning how to maintain and troubleshoot automation used in manufacturing.

- Mentored by a senior service technician, installed safety measures to prevent the operation of a press while the door was opened.
- Wrote PLC logic that uses limit switches to monitor water levels in a holding tank and to drain the tank once the high limit was reached.
- Assisted in the troubleshooting and repair of FANUC industrial arms and HPDC machines.

Education and Skills

Tech Elevator | .NET Web Application Development Bootcamp **Marion Technical College** | A.A.S. Electrical Engineering Technology

Completed 12/2021 Graduated 08/2021

MongoDB | Express | Redis | Node.js | Axios | Apollo GraphQL | Docker | Doppler | Next.js | Retool | .NET | C# | Salesforce | Apex | SOQL | ChatGPT | Git | Postman | Clickup | Jira | Datadog | Integration & Unit Testing | API Mocking | Agile | REST APIs